A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Ford Foundation Fund files FA715
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Ford Foundation Fund files
1949-1973, Bulk, 1950-1960
1950-1960
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA715
3.61 Cubic Feet 9 letter document boxes, 1 half-letter document boxes.
Scope and Contents note
The Ford Foundation Fund files consist of correspondence, summaries of grant actions, charts, listing grant totals, excerpts from dockets and minutes of Trustees meetings, reports, budgets and recommendations, all of which reflect the Foundation's grant-related activities from 1949-1973, with the bulk of the records documenting 1950-1960.
The files provide important background material on the operations of the Foundation from its earliest grant making days through the early 1970s.
Arrangement note
Original order of the records has been maintained.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Michigan Fund Grants: Treasurer's File, 1950 December-1954 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Fund File "A"
  - Miscellaneous Grants: Michigan Fund, 1949 May-1973 January (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Fund File "D"
  - Exchange of Persons: Grants Authorized, 1951-1953 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Fund File "F"
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1962 June-1964 October (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1960 March-1961 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1958 March-1959 October (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1957 January-September (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1955 December-1956 December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1954 February-1955 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development, 1951 May-1953 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Near East-Ford Fund for Overseas Development: Attachment File, 1951 October-1956 May (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Fund File "H"
  - President's Discretionary Fund, 1951 September-1953 November (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Fund File "I"
  - India Program, 1956 March-October (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - India Program, 1955 January-November (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - India Program, 1951 December-1954 December (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - India Program, 1954 February-1963 July (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - India Program, 1962 December-1963 September (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - India Program, 1961 January-December (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - India Program, 1960 January-December (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - India Program, 1959 January-December (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - India Program, 1957 January-1958 December (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Fund File "J"
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1962 March-1963 September (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1961 March-December (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1960 January-December (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1959 January-December (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1958 January-December (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1957 March-November (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1956 February-October (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1955 January-December (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1954 January-December (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1952 October, 1953 January-December (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Pakistan Program: Correspondence, 1951 September-December (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Pakistan Program: Attachment File, 1951 October, 1956 January (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Fund File "M"
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1954 January-1956 July (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1953 May-December (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1953 January-April (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1952 June-December (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1951 August-1952 May (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1952 October-1953 February (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Board on Overseas Training, 1952 March-August (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Board on Overseas Training: Attachment File, 1951 December-1952 June (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Fund File "N"
  - Burma Program, 1952 October-1961 March (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Burma Program, 1960 January-December (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Burma Program, 1959 April-December (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Burma Program, 1957 March-April (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Burma Program, 1956 January-September (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Burma Program, 1955 January-December (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Burma Program, 1954 August-December (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Burma Program, 1954 January-July (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Burma Program, 1952 September-1953 November (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Burma Program: Introduction/Indonesia/Burma, 1952 September (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Fund File "O" (Box 5)
  - Indonesia Program, 1958 January-1960 December (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Indonesia Program, 1961 February-1963 December (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Indonesia Program, 1957 February-December (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Indonesia Program, 1956 February-September (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Indonesia Program, 1955 February-November (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Indonesia Program, 1952 April-1954 January (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Indonesia Program: Attachment File, 1961 December (Box 5, Folder 58)
- Fund File "P" (Box 5)
  - Public Affairs Program, 1964 May-September (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Public Affairs Program, 1952 January-1963 September (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Public Affairs Program: Attachment File (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Fund File "Q" (Box 5)
  - Iran Program, 1953 September-1963 August (Box 5, Folder 62)
- Fund File "R" (Box 6)
  - Education Program, 1964 February-June (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Education Program, 1961 September-1963 December (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Education Program, 1958 September-1959 September (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Education Program, 1954 December-1957 December (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Education Program: Attachment File, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Fund File "S"
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1957 January, 1958 March (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1956 June-December (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1956 April-May (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1956 January-March (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 November-December (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1954 October (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 August-September (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 June-July (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 May (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 April (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1955 January-March (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1954 October-December (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health, 1954 May-September (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health: Attachment File, 1954 May-1956 July (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health: Attachment File, 1953 November, 1954 September (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health: Attachment File, 1954 May-1957 September (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health: Attachment File, 1955 Summer (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Research and Training in Mental Health: Attachment File, 1953 November (Box 8, Folder 85)
- Fund File "T" (Box 8)
  - Program for Europe, 1956 October -1964 October (Box 8, Folder 85A)
- Fund File "U" (Box 8)
  - Humanities and Arts Program, 1963 September-1968 August (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Humanities and Arts Program, 1959 June-1962 October (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Humanities and Arts Program, 1956 March-1958 July (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Humanities and Arts Program, 1955 November-1956 March (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Humanities and Arts Program: Attachment File, 1960 March-1965 September (Box 8, Folder 90)
- Fund File "V"
  - Program in Latin America, 1963 January-1964 December (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Program in Latin America, 1961 April-1962 December (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Program in Latin America, 1957 June-1960 July (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Program in Latin America: Attachment File, 1960 June, 1963 February (Box 9, Folder 94)
- Fund File "W" (Box 9)
  - Program in Africa, 1962 June-1964 January (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Program in Africa, 1956 June-1961 December (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Program in Africa: Attachment File, 1957 January-1958 July (Box 9, Folder 97)
- Fund File "X" (Box 9)
  - Program in Science and Engineering, 1960 May-1964 February (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Program in Science and Engineering, 1954 December-1959 November (Box 9, Folder 99)
- Fund File "Y"
  - Overseas Development Program, 1955 February-1956 December (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1954 February-June (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1951 October-1953 November (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1964 May-1966 October (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1962 February-1963 December (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1961 February-December (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1960 January-December (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Overseas Development Program, 1957 May-1959 June (Box 10, Folder 107)